Jonathan Hinestroza

+57 3147416121 | jonathanhinestroza87@gmail.com | Medellin Colombia, Medellin, Antioquia

Summary

Java Software Developer with over 4 years of experience . I have developed microservices using Java, Spring Boot, Docker, Kafka and also I have worked with Angular in Front-end and working with CI/CD technologies. I have worked in teams with Scrum and Kanban methodologies. I am a responsible, agile, and autodidactic developer analyzing and proposing quality solutions. I am committed to my work with a sense of belonging. I like to update my knowledge continually with cutting-edge technologies in software development. I enjoy coding and improving my skills with clean and extensible good practices.

Experience

NTT Data Europe & Latam | Medellín, Antioquia

Java Software Engineer | 06/2022- Today

Microservices Developer with Java technologies for Oil, Gas and Energy sector. Scrum development methodology. Deployed, Scaled, Configured, wrote manifest file for various Microservices. Implemented REST Microservices using Spring Boot Framework. Generated Metrics with method level granularity and Persistence Spring Actuator.

Environment: Java 11+, Restfull web Services (Spring Boot), Spring Config server, Angular, HTML, JSON, Log4j, Maven, Git, Junit, Mockito, Tomcat 9, CD (continuous deployment), Sonar Cloud, Asynchronous Messaging with GCP Pub/Sub, Azure DevOps, Docker, Spring Cloud, Relational Database on GCP Data Store, NoSql with DynamoDB, API Gateway pattern with GCP APIGEE.

Globant | Medellín, Antioquia

Java Software Developer | 12/2020 - 02/2022

Microservices Developer with Java technologies.

Spring Boot. Deployed, Scaled, Configured, wrote manifest file for various Microservices. Implemented REST Microservices using spring boot. Generated Metrics with method level granularity and Persistence Spring Actuator.

Implemented Zipkins for distributed Micro Service Monitoring. Integrated Swagger UI for rest services, GraphiQL for GraphQL services and wrote integration test along with REST document. Implemented Hysterix a Latency and Fault Tolerance system for Distributed Systems. Wrote Controller, Services.

Used spring config server for centralized configuration and Splunk for centralized logging. Used Concourse and Jenkins for Microservices deployment. Developed story/task by following TDD/BDD and Pair programming concepts. Providing daily status in scrum meetings with the client.

Environment: Java 11+, Kotlin and Scala Restfull and GraphQL web Services (Spring Boot), Zipkins, Hystrix, Spring Config server, Angular, HTML, JSON, Log4j, Maven and Gradle, Git, Junit, Mockito, Tomcat 9, CD (continuous deployment), Open Shift, Asynchronous Messaging with Apache Kafka, DevOps with Docker, Spring Cloud, Relational Database, NoSql, API gateway pattern, Jenkins.

Experis | Medellín, Antioquia

Senior Java Developer | 09/2020 - 12/2020

Java 8+, PLSQL, Web Services, Struts 1, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MVC, JSP, Oracle Database 11g.

Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.

Built web applications using Struts 1 framework. Diagnosed and corrected errors within code to allow for integration of proprietary applications. Performed unit testing, system testing and integration testing

Freelance/Self Employed | Medellín, Antioquia

Middle Java Software Developer | 11/2019 - 10/2020

Microservices Developer with Java technologies.

Responsibilities:

Converted a monolithic app to microservices architecture using Spring Boot. Deployed, Scaled, Configured, wrote manifest file for various Microservices in AWS.

Implemented REST Microservices using spring boot. Generated Metrics with method level granularity and Persistence using Spring AOP and Spring Actuator. Used spring config server for centralized configuration and Splunk for centralized logging. Used Concourse and Jenkins for Microservices deployment Developed story/task by following TDD/BDD and Pair programming concepts. Providing daily status in scrum meetings with the client.

Environment: Java 8+, Restful web Services (Spring Boot), Zipkins, Hystrix, Spring Config server, Angular JS1.x, HTML, JSON, Log4j, Maven, Git, Junit, Tomcat 9, CD (continuous deployment), Asynchronous Messaging with Apache Kafka, DevOps with Docker and Kubernetes clusters, AWS, Spring Cloud, Relational Database, NoSql, API gateway pattern, Jenkins.

Independent Consultancy | Medellín, Antioquia

Middle Java Software Developer | 10/2018 - 11/2019

Worked with business teams to understand needs and address production questions. My role was to create microservices and Restful Apis. I also monitor and process pull requests for production deployments. Performed troubleshooting and diagnostics to uncover root malfunctions.

Reviewed code and debugged errors to improve performance. Optimized web assets for speed and performance. Determined coding requirements for specialized scripts.

Technologies used:

Java, Angular, JavaScript, ES6, TypeScript, Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Maven, MySql, GIT, Docker, Docker-Compose.

Invamer | Medellín, Antioquia

Junior Software Developer | 10/2017 - 10/2018

Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality. Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development. Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements. Designed customized solutions for proposals to potential customers.

Technologies used:

Spring boot, Java EE, JQuery, Html, CSS, JavaScript.

Links

GitHub

https://github.com/SoulMan87

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-hinestroza/

Languages

English, Spanish

Skills

Spring Boot, Docker, Kafka, Angular, Java 8+, Microservices, Cloud Computing, AWS, GCP, Typescript, JUnit, Maven, Jenkins, Git, Scala.

Education

Servicio Nacional De Aprendizaje | Medellín, Antioquia

Information Technology | 12/2021

Graduated

Servicio Nacional De Aprendizaje | Medellín, Antioquia

Software Development | 02/2019

• Graduated

Politecnico Grancolombiano | Medellín, Antioquia

Software Engineering | 08/2024

• Currently completing courses in computer science.